let's see the geometry behind the
infinite sum of the powers of one-fifth
start with a one by one square if we
connect the vertices to the midpoints
like this it turns out that we divide
the square into five equal pieces the
four Triangles around the outside and
the inner Square all consist of
one-fifth of the area of the square so
this triangle is one-fifth but then we
can repeat the process on the inner
Square to get one-fifth of one-fifth and
so on we can continue this process
indefinitely each time taking one-fifth
of the inner Square which is one-fifth
of the previous Square we spiral this
down forever and it turns out that we've
shaded one-fifth plus one-fifth squared
and so on of the entire Square
but this shape can be rotated three more
times to fill in the entire Square
therefore the infinite sum of powers of
one-fifth must be one-fourth
foreign